Guide to the Verstille Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Verstille family papers
1754-1858
MS 522
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3.5
(2 boxes, 1 folio)
The principal figures in these papers are Peter Verstille of Wethersfield and Hartford, Connecticut, his wife Naomi Ridgway Verstille, their children and grandchildren. Most of the papers consist of correspondence, but also included are financial and legal papers, among them accounts of the estate of Peter Verstille and lists of house furnishings. The largest part of the correspondence is the exchange of letters between Nancy and Charlotte Verstille, grandaughters of Peter Verstille. Both were teachers and discuss their experiences at schools in various parts of New England and the South. The letters of Nancy Verstille also include an account of an operation performed in 1817. The Dabney family of Massachusetts were major correspondents and their letters contain a description of the bankruptcy of the family in 1818.
Verstille family
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Richard J. Hooker, 1955.
Scope and Contents
The papers, 1754-1858, of the Verstille family of Connecticut consist largely of correspondence, although some business and financial papers are also included. The approximately 600 letters are arranged by family member. Each item and all correspondents are listed in the register.
The papers of the merchant Peter Verstille of Wethersfield and Hartford, Connecticut, and his wife Naomi (Ridgway) Verstille consist of letters from business associates and family members, dealing almost entirely with business matters. One particularly interesting letter comes to Verstille from Enoch Brown (1778 May 12), announcing his decision to sell a favorite slave due to anti-slavery agitation in Boston.
There is a small amount of family and business correspondence of Peter and Naomi's daughter-in-law Eliza Verstille and of her sons William, Tristram, and Seldon, and daughter-in-law Rebecca, but the largest portion of the collection by far is made up of the correspondence of Eliza's daughters Nancy and Charlotte. These are letters which the two sisters exchanged with each other, with family members, and with friends, especially members of the Dabney family of Salem, Massachusetts, during the first half of the nineteenth century. Charlotte taught at the Franklin Academy in Andover, Massachusetts, for some years, and then at a variety of places in New England and the South, as did Nancy, and their activities at their various schools are a frequent topic in their letters. Other often-discussed matters are Charlotte's determination to stay single and devote herself to teaching and religion, news of family and friends, church and social events, and the health of the sisters. Nancy suffered from a tumor that was surgically removed in September of 1817, and her letters describe the disease and recovery; there are also several letters from her doctor, John G. Warren. The letters of the Dabneys are concerned with all these matters and with the bankruptcy of their family in 1818, and a host of other family problems. The letters of William Caton to Charlotte describe his journey to Oswego and Sacketts Harbor, New York, and his duties as a naval surgeon before and during the War of 1812.
The collection contains a small amount of correspondence of Naomi Verstille's third husband, Rev. Joseph Perry, largely letters from fellow ministers concerned with church matters. His correspondents include James Dana, Selleck Silliman, and Chauncey Whittelsey. Also among his papers are a sermon, a letter to his son, and a letter to the father of his slave concerning the boy's purchase (1792). The remaining correspondence in the collection consists of letters, many of them unidentified, to others than Verstille family members. The collection is completed by an assortment of bills, receipts, accounts, estate papers, and miscellaneous items such as lists of furnishings and calling cards, arranged chronologically.
Many of the items are in fragile condition and must be handled with care.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
For a chart outlining the genealogical relations of the Verstille family, please consult the Genealogical Chart.
Bankruptcy -- Massachusetts; Brothers and sisters; Families; Medicine -- 19th century; Slavery -- United States; Surgery -- Case studies; Surgery -- Statistics; Women -- Education; Connecticut; New England; United States -- History -- Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775; United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783; United States -- History -- War of 1812; Educators; Women teachers; Bromfield, Thomas; Browne, John; Buck, Catharine; Caton, William; Dabney, Abigail Mason Peale, 1767-; Tudor, Elizabeth Dabney; Dabney, Margaret; Dana, James, 1735-1812; Henshaw, Benjamin; Hughes, Samuel; Mears, Stephen; Mitchell, Samuel M.; Perry, Joseph, 1731-1783; Ridgway, Sam H., 1936-; Ruggles, Samuel; Silliman, Selleck; Stebbins, Susan; Tudor, Sophia; Verstille, Charlotte Lydia Sheldon, b. 1787; Verstille, Nancy Olds, 1781-1861; Verstille, Naomi Ridgway, d. 1785; Verstille, Peter, 1734-1778; Verstille, William Henry, 1783-1804; Whittelsey, Chauncey, 1783-1834; Dabney family; Verstille family; United States. Navy ( Surgeons)
- Inventory, 1754-1858, undated
  - Peter Verstille: incoming letters
    - Richard Alsop, Middletown, 1766 February 17 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Edward Best, Boston
      - 1755 April 7 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 1755 June 16 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Sarah Bradford, Boston, 1765 October 8 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Thomas Bromfield, Boston
      - 1761December 22 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 1762 June 9 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 1762 August 19 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 1762 September 9 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 1762 December 24 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 1763 February 17 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 1763 September 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 1763 October 13 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 1764 March 7 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 1765 March 23 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Enoch Brown, Boston, 1778 May 12 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - James Browne, Portsmouth, 1754 September 19 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - John Browne, Boston
      - 1764 December 18 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - 1766 June 25 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - 1766 July 15 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - 1766 August 19 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Benjamin Carnes, Boston, 1756 October 2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - John Carnes, Boston, 1756 October 11 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Richard Champney, Boston, 1755 June 3 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - William Clark, Dedham, 1775 July 27 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Alexander Cochran, Boston, 1754 August 6 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Edward Foster, Boston, 1754 June 11 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - J.W. Gibbs
      - New York, 1775 October 18 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Bethlehem, 1777 November 29 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Sam Hardcastle, Boston, 1755 June 30 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Benjamin Henshaw, Middletown
      - 1765 August 3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 1766 August 9 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 1776 March 9 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Samuel Hughes, Boston
      - 1755 January 27 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 1755 February 17 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 1755 February 24 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 1755 March 17 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 1755 March 18 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 1755 March 31 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 1755 April 28 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 1755 September 9 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Peter Hughes, Boston, 1768 September 30 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Robert Jenkins, Boston, 1764 August 30 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Stephen Mears, Hartford
      - 1772 December 15 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 1774 February 21 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 1773 April 5 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 1773 June 28 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 1773 September 27 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 1774 April 25 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 1774 September 5 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Samuel M. Mitchell, Wethersfield
      - 1772 July 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 1773 October 17 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 1774 April 27 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Joseph Pease, Suffield, 1773 July 26 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - John Raynolds, Enfield, 1773 June 5 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Philip Ridgway, Boston, 1769 October 12 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Samuel Ridgway
      - No place, 1761 September 14 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Boston (Box 1)
        - 1762 September 16 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - 1763 May 12 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - 1765 May 23 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - 1766 September 18 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - 1764 November 10 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - 1769 August 23 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - 1769 September 28 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - 1770 August 30 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Samuel Ruggles, Boston
      - 1776 September 15 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - 1777 January 30 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - 1777 July 23 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - 1778 January 14 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Josiah and William Russell, Providence, 1769 November 28 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Solomon Smith, Hartford, 1773 April 26 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Naomi Verstille
      - Boston, 1768 April 22 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Hartford, 1773 May 11 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Wethersfield, [no year] July 18 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Nathaniel Warner, Boston
      - 1765 October 10 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - 1761 June 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Nathaniel Wheatley, Boston, 1766 March 19 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Abijah Willard, Lancaster, 1773 June 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Josiah Willard
      - Hartford, 1773 May 26 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Newington, 1773 July 5 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Portion of note of Thos. Wooster, no place, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Naomi (Ridgeway) Gedney Verstille Perry: incoming letters
    - Caleb Blanchard, Boston, 1769 March 24 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Elisha Callender, Wethersfield, 1785 March 11 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Justin Ely, West Springfield, 1784 December 2 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - J. Green, Westfield, 1783 August 5 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Benjamin Henshaw, Middletown
      - 1783 April 22 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - 1784 October 2 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Elenor Lyman, Suffield, 1773 July 23 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Samuel Lyman, Springfield, 1785 April 7 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - J. Perry, Springfield, 1783 May 5 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - John Raynolds, Enfield, 1768 October 11 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Samuel Ridgway, Boston
      - 1763 July 27 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - 1768 October 27 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - 1769 March 23 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - 1769 April 6 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - 1769 April 20 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - 1769 October 17 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - (unsigned, nephew), Philadelphia, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Charlotte Verstille
    - Incoming letters
      - Caton, William, Jr. (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
        - From Utica, 1810 August 19 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - From Oswego
          - 1810 August 14 (Box 1, Folder 9)
          - 1810 September 3 (Box 1, Folder 9)
          - 1810 September 28 (Box 1, Folder 9)
          - 1810 October 9 (Box 1, Folder 9)
          - 1810 November 4 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - From Sackets Harbor
          - 1810 November 26 (Box 1, Folder 9)
          - 1810 December 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
          - 1810 December 22 (Box 1, Folder 9)
          - 1811 February 12 (Box 1, Folder 9)
          - 1811 March 30 (Box 1, Folder 10)
          - 1811 May 20 (Box 1, Folder 10)
        - From Brig Oneida, Sackets Harbor, 1811 July 11 (Box 1, Folder 10)
        - From Schooner Collector, Lake Ontario, 1811October 26
          - Enclosing letter from Capt. Woolsey, 1811 November 8 (Box 1, Folder 10)
        - From Sackets Harbor, [1811?] (Box 1, Folder 10)
        - From U.S. Schooner Sylphe, 1813 September 20 (Box 1, Folder 10)
        - From Vergennes, Vt., 1814 March 11 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Dabney, Abigail Mason
        - From Salem
          - 1800 February 25 (Box 1, Folder 11)
          - 1807 June 7 (Box 1, Folder 11)
          - 1816 February 19 (Box 1, Folder 11)
          - 1816 June 28 (Box 1, Folder 11)
          - 1818 March 24 (Box 1, Folder 11)
          - 1818 April 15 (Box 1, Folder 12)
          - 1818 April 22 (Box 1, Folder 12)
        - No place, 1818 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 12)
        - From Salem
          - 1818 June 12 (Box 1, Folder 12)
          - 1818 June 25 (Box 1, Folder 12)
          - 1819 January 11 (Box 1, Folder 12)
          - 1819 March 7 (Box 1, Folder 12)
          - 1819 April 4 (Box 1, Folder 12)
          - 1819 April 26 (Box 1, Folder 12)
          - 1819 June 19 (Box 1, Folder 13)
        - To Sophia Tudor, from Boston, 1821 June 16 (Box 1, Folder 13)
        - To Charlotte Verstille, from Boston, September 16 [1821?] (Box 1, Folder 13)
        - To Elizabeth Tudor, from Salem, 1823 January 22 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Dabney, Elizabeth G. (Box 1, Folder 14-19)
        - From Salem, 1808 May 30 (Box 1, Folder 14)
        - No place, 1808 June 6 (Box 1, Folder 14)
        - From Salem
          - 1809 October 15 (Box 1, Folder 14)
          - 1809 December 10 (Box 1, Folder 14)
        - No place
          - 1810 January 30 (Box 1, Folder 14)
          - 1810 February 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
          - 1810 February 5 (Box 1, Folder 14)
          - 1810 April 16 (Box 1, Folder 14)
          - 1810 May 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
          - 1810 August 21 (Box 1, Folder 14)
          - 1811 November 13 (Box 1, Folder 14)
          - 1812 May (Box 1, Folder 15)
          - 1812 May 7 (Box 1, Folder 15)
          - 1812 May 19 (Box 1, Folder 15)
          - 1812 June 12 (Box 1, Folder 15)
          - 1812 August 23 (Box 1, Folder 15)
          - 1812 October 4 (Box 1, Folder 15)
          - 1812 October 25 (Box 1, Folder 15)
        - From Salem, 1812 November 9 (Box 1, Folder 15)
        - No place, 1813 September 20 (Box 1, Folder 15)
        - From Salem, 1813 December 28 (Box 1, Folder 15)
        - No place
          - 1814 February 4 (Box 1, Folder 15)
          - 1814 March 4 (Box 1, Folder 15)
          - 1814 October 30 (Box 1, Folder 15)
          - 1814 November 15 (Box 1, Folder 16)
          - 1814 November 27 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        - From Salem
          - 1814 December 22 (Box 1, Folder 16)
          - 1815 January 5 (Box 1, Folder 16)
          - 1815 March 8 (Box 1, Folder 16)
          - 1815 March 26 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        - No place, 1815 April 18 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        - From Salem, 1816 February 12 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        - No place, 1816 March 29 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        - From Salem
          - 1816 April 7 (Box 1, Folder 16)
          - 1816 May 20 (Box 1, Folder 16)
          - 1816 August 13 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        - No place, 1816 October 8 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        - From Salem
          - 1816 December 11 (Box 1, Folder 17)
          - 1816 December 24 (Box 1, Folder 17)
          - 1817 February 15 (Box 1, Folder 17)
          - 1817 March 1 (Box 1, Folder 17)
          - 1817 March 25 (Box 1, Folder 17)
          - 1817 September 18 (Box 1, Folder 17)
          - 1817 September 12 (Box 1, Folder 17)
        - No place, 1817 November 2 (Box 1, Folder 17)
        - From Salem
          - 1817 December 8 (Box 1, Folder 17)
          - 1817 December 24 (Box 1, Folder 17)
        - From Boston
          - 1818 January 15 (Box 1, Folder 18)
          - 1818 January 20 (Box 1, Folder 18)
        - From Salem
          - 1818 February 7 (Box 1, Folder 18)
          - 1818 March 3 (Box 1, Folder 18)
          - 1818 April 28 (Box 1, Folder 18)
        - No place, 1818 May 14 (Box 1, Folder 18)
        - From Salem, 1818 May 7 (Box 1, Folder 18)
        - No place, 1818 May 19 (Box 1, Folder 18)
        - From Salem
          - 1819 August 15 (Box 1, Folder 18)
          - 1819 September 23 (Box 1, Folder 18)
        - From Chelsea, 1820 October 29 (Box 1, Folder 18)
        - No place
          - Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
          - Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
          - Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
        - From Gloucester, Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
        - From Salem, Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
        - No place
          - Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
          - Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
          - Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
          - Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
          - Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
          - Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
        - Unaddressed letter from Elizabeth Dabney (Box 1, Folder 19)
        - Letter from Elizabeth Dabney to Mr. and Mrs. Tuckerman, no place, Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - J.S. Beekman, Bloomingdale, 1813 January 18 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - C.E. Belden, Fayetteville, N.C., Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Catharine Buck
        - From Andover
          - 1812 December 18 (Box 1, Folder 20)
          - 1813 March 17 (Box 1, Folder 20)
        - New York, 1813 October 5 (Box 1, Folder 20)
        - From Andover
          - 1814 February 15 (Box 1, Folder 20)
          - 1815 April 2 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - H.F. Catlin, New Marlborough, 1817 June 2 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Martin Curtis, Granville, 1846 December 16 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Margaret Dabney, Salem, 1818 April 27 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Ann Grant, East Windsor, 1812 June 29 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - P.W. Grant, East Windsor, 1820 August 4 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - C.T. Haigh, Fayetteville, N.C., 1821 October 23 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - W.K.
        - Salem, 1810 January 7 (Box 1, Folder 21)
        - Boston
          - 1812 December 29 (Box 1, Folder 21)
          - 1812 February 13 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Glen King, Salem, 1811 June 14 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - C. Kittredge, Andover, 1814 April 4 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - B. Loring, Andover, 1815 April 18 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - J. Millet, Newark
        - 1812 June 28 (Box 1, Folder 21)
        - 1812 August 9 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Milo North
        - North Marlborough, 1810 May 29 (Box 1, Folder 21)
        - Salisbury, 1815 June 7 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - H. Osgood, Andover, 1811 December 29 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Harriot Osgood
        - Westfield, 1813 September 7 (Box 1, Folder 22)
        - Andover, 1812 February 2 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Hannah Osgood, Andover, 1817 April 29 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - J. Osgood, no place, Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Nancy Read, Belfast, 1809 February 3 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - P.G. Robbins, no place, Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Peter Gilman Robbins
        - Lynn, 1812 November 25 (Box 1, Folder 22)
        - No place, Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - L.P. Seaver, Fayetteville, 1821 February 25 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Benjamin Stebbins, Boston, 1815 December 24 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - William Stebbins, Windsor, 1814 January 29 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Susan Stebbins
        - Salem
          - 1809 September 30 (Box 1, Folder 23)
          - 1810 February 4 (Box 1, Folder 23)
          - 1810 March 20 (Box 1, Folder 23)
          - 1810 May 10 (Box 1, Folder 23)
          - 1810 September 5 (Box 1, Folder 23)
        - Gloucester, 1811 June 29 (Box 1, Folder 23)
        - No place, Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
        - Salem, Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
        - No place, Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Sophia Tudor
        - East Windsor
          - 1819 October 16 (Box 1, Folder 24)
          - Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
        - No place, Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Chas. W. Wooster, New York, 1815 December 4 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Wm. Verstille, Bordeaux, 1804 August 2 (Box 1, Folder 24)
        - Unsigned, East Windsor, 1823 August 18 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Unsigned, Boston, Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Unsigned, no place, Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Harriet East Windsor, Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Outgoing letters
      - Elizabeth Dabney, from East Windsor, 1809 October 3 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Nancy Verstille
        - New York, 1810 September 5 (Box 1, Folder 25)
        - East Windsor, 1810 October 19 (Box 1, Folder 25)
        - No place, 1810 November 12 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Eliza Verstille, from Andover, 1811 October 21 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Nancy Verstille, from Salem
        - 1812 January 3 (Box 1, Folder 25)
        - 1812 January 6 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Eliza Verstille, from Salem, 1812 January 31 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Nancy Verstille, from Andover, 1812 March 8 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Eliza Verstille, from Andover, 1812 September 12 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Nancy Verstille
        - From Andover, 1812 October 18 (Box 1, Folder 25)
        - From Salem, 1812 December 12 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Eliza Verstille, from Salem, 1813 January 11 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Nancy Verstille, from Salem, 1813 March 20 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Eliza Verstille, from Andover, 1813 April 29 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Nancy Verstille, from Andover, 1813 July 17 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Eliza Verstille, from Andover, 1814 April 28 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Nancy Verstille, from Andover, 1814 July 11 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Eliza Verstille, from Andover
        - 1814 July 29 (Box 1, Folder 26)
        - 1814 September 14 (Box 1, Folder 26)
        - 1814 September 26 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Nancy Verstille
        - Andover, 1814 October 13 (Box 1, Folder 26)
        - East Windsor, 1814 December 4 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Eliza Verstille, from Andover, 1815 May 5 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Nancy Verstille
        - From Andover
          - 1815 June 11 (Box 2, Folder 27)
          - 1815 July 4 (Box 2, Folder 27)
          - 1815 September 16 (Box 2, Folder 27)
        - New York, 1816 May 4 (Box 2, Folder 27)
        - East Windsor
          - 1817 September 11 (Box 2, Folder 27)
          - 1817 September 22 (Box 2, Folder 27)
          - 1817 November 1 (Box 2, Folder 27)
          - 1818 January 21 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Unidentified, from East Windsor, 1818 February (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Nancy Verstille
        - East Windsor
          - 1818 March 5 (Box 2, Folder 27)
          - 1818 March 7 (Box 2, Folder 27)
        - Fayetteville
          - 1819 May 13 (Box 2, Folder 28)
          - 1819 September 27 (Box 2, Folder 28)
          - 1820 April 1 (Box 2, Folder 28)
          - 1820 July 22 (Box 2, Folder 28)
          - 1820 October 18 (Box 2, Folder 28)
          - 1820 December 20 (Box 2, Folder 28)
        - New Haven
          - 1824 January 3 (Box 2, Folder 28)
          - 1824 January 30 (Box 2, Folder 28)
          - 1824 March 18 (Box 2, Folder 28)
          - 1824 April 12 (Box 2, Folder 28)
          - 1839 July 30 (Box 2, Folder 28)
          - 1839 November 4 (Box 2, Folder 28)
        - Tybee Light House, 1839 November 19 (Box 2, Folder 28)
        - Athens, Georgia, 1847 August 18 (Box 2, Folder 28)
        - Columbus, 1856 October 18 (Box 2, Folder 28)
        - E. Tennessee, 1857 August 22 (Box 2, Folder 29)
        - No place, Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
        - New Haven, Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
        - No place, Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
        - East Windsor, Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
        - No place, Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
        - New Haven, Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Eliza Verstille, no place
        - Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
        - Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Nancy Verstille
    - Incoming letters
      - Dabney, Abigail Mason
        - From Salem
          - 1804 February 1 (Box 2, Folder 30)
          - 1816 October 10 (Box 2, Folder 30)
          - 1818 September 7 (Box 2, Folder 30)
        - No place
          - 1818 September 10 (Box 2, Folder 30)
          - 1818 September 27 (Box 2, Folder 30)
        - From Salem
          - 1819 February 22 (Box 2, Folder 30)
          - 1819 August 23 (Box 2, Folder 30)
          - 1819 September 24 (Box 2, Folder 30)
          - 1819 October 18 (Box 2, Folder 30)
          - 1820 April 2 (Box 2, Folder 31)